Guide to the Amos Poe Papers, 1966-2005 MSS.203
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series IX: Video
  - Series IX, Subseries A: Access Copies
    - CBGB's Second Avenue Theater - Film Footage - Edited Excerpt, December, 1978; ID: 203.0480 (Box Shared Fales 143, Dvd 203.0480)
      Duration: 00:12:42
  - Series IX, Subseries B: Originals
    - "Amos Poe Sample Reel", May 15, 1985; ID: 203.0471 (Box 52, Media ID: 203.0471)
      Format: Helical Video Tape
      Track List: 1. Run DMC, "You Talk Too Much" 2. Animotion, "Obsession" 3. Raven, "On and On" 4. Johnny Van Zant, "I'm a Fighter" 5. Humpe-Humpe, "Three of Us" 6. Juice Newton, "Can't Wait All Night" 7. Van Stephenson, "What the Big Girls Do"
    - [Assorted Footage 1], various (Box 55)
      This is a collection of 96 original video elements.
      Format: Mini DV, DV Cam, Hi8
    - [Assorted Footage 2], various (Box 56)
      This is a collection of 79 original video elements.
      Format: Mini DV
    - [Assorted Footage 3], various (Box 59)
      This is an assortment of 33 original video elements.
      Format: Betacam, VHS
    - [Assorted Footage 4], various (Box 60)
      This is an assortment of 43 original video elements.
    - The Blank Generation, 1976; ID: 203.0230 (Box 52)
      Black and White, Sound
      Duration: 00:55:00
      Content: A film by Amos Poe & Ivan Kral. Distributed by Pokra Pictures
      The cream of New York new wave/punk filmed live at CBGB's when the scene was just beginning. Includes performances by Patti Smith, Blondie, Television, the Ramones, Talking Heads, the Heartbreakers, the Shirts, Wayne County, the Marbles, the New York Dolls, Miamis, Harry Toledo, and the Tuff Darts (w/Robert Gordon).
    - [Directed by Amos Poe 1], 1976 - 1994 (Box 45)
      This is a collection of 45 videos directed by Amos Poe.
    - [Directed by Amos Poe 2], 1998 - 2003 (Box 46)
      This is a collection of 27 video elements directed by Amos Poe.
      Format: U-Matic, DV Cam, VHS, DVD
      Duration: [various]
    - "The Films of Amos Poe", April 19, 1996; ID: 203.0470 (Box 52, Media ID: 203.0470)
      Format: Betacam SP
    - The Foreigner, 1978; ID: 203.0240 (Box 52)
      Starring Eric Mitchell, Debbie Harry
      European secret agent Max Menace arrives in New York City, waiting for his contact to tell him his assignment. He becomes entangled with an assortment of odd characters and situations, but never learns why he's there.
    - "John the Cop" (Tapes 1 - 12), 1996 (Box 47)
    - "John the Cop" (Tapes 13 - 24), 1996 (Box 48)
    - "John the Cop" (Tapes 25 - 36), 1996 (Box 49)
    - "John the Cop" (Tapes 37 - 48), 1996 (Box 50)
    - "John the Cop" (Tapes 49 - 51), 1996 (Box 51)
    - "John the Cop" (Tapes 001 - 003), 1996 (Box 51)
    - "John the Cop" (Beta Masters 1), 1996 (Box 51)
      This is a collection of 10 original video elements.
      Format: Betacam SP, VHS
    - "John the Cop" (Beta Masters 2), 1996 (Box 52)
      This is a collection of 13 original video elements.
    - "John the Cop" (Hi8 Footage 1), 1996 (Box 53)
      This is a collection of 48 original video elements.
      Format: Hi-8
    - "John the Cop" (Hi8 Footage 2), 1996 (Box 54)
      This is a collection of 47 original video elements.
    - [Music Video Footage], 1984 - 1985 (Box 58)
      This is a collection of 8 original video elements.
      Format: U-Matic, Betacam
    - [Produced by Amos Poe], various (Box 57)
      This is a collection of 21 original video elements.
      Format: U-Matic, VHS
  - Series IX, Subseries C: Miscellaneous Video
    - [Commercial Video 1], various (Box 61)
      This is a collection of 34 videos from Amos Poe's personal library.
    - [Commercial Video 2], various (Box 62)
      This is a collection of 28 videos from Amos Poe's personal library.
      Format: DVD, VHS
  - Subseries D: Submasters - CLOSED
    CLOSED
    - St. Mark's Place Massacre, Ark of Destiny, 2009-05-20 (Box Shared Fales PM 7, Case 203.0217)
    - Ballad of a Thin Woman, Knife in the Rain, 2009-05-20 (Box Shared Fales PM 7, Case 203.0220)
    - My, My Michaelangelo, 2010-08-11 (Box Shared Fales PM 7, Case 203.0228)
    - CBGB New Year's Eve, 1978 (Box Shared Fales PM 10, Case 203.0473)
      Source ID
      203.0112
    - CBGB's 2nd Avenue Theater film footage reel two (Box Shared Fales PM 10)
    - CBGB Theater New Year's Eve, 1978, edited excerpts for 2010 Orphan Film Symposium (Box Shared Fales PM 10, Case 203.0479)
      203.0112A
  - Subseries E: Preservation Masters - CLOSED
    - CBGB Theater New Year's Eve [excerpts], 1978 (Box Shared Fales PM 69, Digital betacam 203.0478)
    - CBGB New Year's Eve, 1978, reel #1, 2010-03-05 (Box Shared Fales PM 69, Case 203.0472)
    - CBGB New Year's Eve, 1978, reel #2, 2010-03-17 (Box Shared Fales PM 69, Case 293.0475)
    - ID: 203.0216, 203.0219, 203.0227 (Box Shared Fales PM 56)
- Series X: Audio
  - Series X, Subseries A: Access Copies
    Audio materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Series X, Subseries B: Originals
    - [Assorted Cassette Recordings], various (Box 65)
      This is a collection of 24 personal audio recordings from Poe's library.
      Format: Audio Cassette
    - "John the Cop" Audio Recordings, 1996 (Box 64)
      This is a collection of 6 original audio production recordings.
      Format: Maxell C120 Audio Cassette
    - [Production Recordings 1], various (Box 63)
      This is a collection of 11 original source and incidental audio elements.
      Format: 1/4", 1" tapes
    - [Production Recordings 2] (Box 64)
      This is an assortment of 99 original source and incidental audio elements.
  - Series X, Subseries C: Miscellaneous Audio
    - [Commercial Audio 1], various (Box 66)
      This is an assortment of 39 audio recordings from Amos Poe's personal library.
      Format: Audio Cassette, CD
    - [Commercial Audio 2: Vinyl], various (Box 67)
      This is a collection of 50 vinyl records from Amos Poe's personal library.
      Format: 7" vinyl record
- Series XI: Objects
  - Buttons and Pins, Assorted, undated; ID: 203.2.0001 (Box 40, Media ID: 203.2.0001)
  - "Movie Stars" Card Game, [1974]; ID: 203.2.0002 (Box 40, Media ID: 203.2.0002)
  - Wall Hamsa (The Israel Museum, Jerusalem), [1969]; ID: 203.2.0003 (Box 40, Media ID: 203.2.0003)
  - Centric Camera Clock, undated; ID: 203.2.0004 (Box 40, Media ID: 203.2.0004)
  - Wooden Stamp, "Amos", undated; ID: 203.2.0005 (Box 40, Media ID: 203.2.0005)
  - Poe Productions Corporate Seals, [1987]; ID: 203.2.0006 (Box 40, Media ID: 203.2.0006)
  - Super 8 Adhesive Tape Splicer, undated; ID: 203.2.0007 (Box 40, Media ID: 203.2.0007)
  - Stamp, "Amos Poe, The Foreigner", undated; ID: 203.2.0008 (Box 40, Media ID: 203.2.0008)
  - Black Coffee Cup, IFP Gotham Awards, ID: 203.2.0009 (Box 40, Media ID: 203.2.0009)
  - Paper Embosser, "Poe Productions, Inc.", 1987; ID: 203.2.0010 (Box 40, Media ID: 203.2.0010)
  - Metal Box, "'Agent Breaker': Petty Cash", undated; ID: 203.2.0011 (Box 40, Media ID: 203.2.0011)
  - Collage, undated; ID: 203.2.0013 (Box 40, Media ID: 203.2.0013)
  - Camera in Leather Case, undated; ID: 203.2.0015 (Box 40, Media ID: 203.2.0015)
  - Pins, "Triple Bogey ", undated; ID: 203.2.0016 (Box 40, Media ID: 203.2.0016)
  - The New Wave Cookbook, 1980; ID: 203.2.0017 (Box 40, Media ID: 203.2.0017)
  - Sex Pistols, "God Save the Queen" [Vinyl], 1977; ID: 203.2.0018 (Box 40, Media ID: 203.2.0018)
- OVERSIZE Series I: Writing
  - Subseries C: Source and Subject Files
    - Arslanian, Melvie, undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
- OVERSIZE Series II: Production Files
  - Subseries A: Administrative
    - "Alphabet City" production plan, undated (Folder 3)
    - "Dead Weekend," storyboards, sketches, etc., [1994] (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - "The Foreigner," notes, undated (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - "The Legend of Maya Deren," Jonas Mekas, [c1977] (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - "Night Witches," storyboard sketches, 2002 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - "Subway Riders," mixing cue sheets, undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - "Subway Riders," storyboard notebook, undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - "Unmade Beds," notes, [June 1976] (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C: Distribution and Promotion
    - "Alphabet City" mock up, [undated] (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Bleeker St. Cinema Flyer mock up, [Jan. 1971] (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - The Larkin Calendar [San Francisco], [1978] (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - "Poe Visions" mock up, [c1978] (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - "Poe Visions" mailer, [1978] (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - "The Blank Generation," posters, undated (Box 43, Folder 2, Folder 4)
    - "The Foreigner," posters and press pack, [1978] (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - "Subway Riders", undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Tape Cover Sketches, "The Blank Generation" and Triple Bogey", undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - "Unmade Beds," posters, undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - "La Pacifica" Poster, 1994 (Folder 19)
  - Subseries D: Film Festivals
    - "The Blank Generation," Los Angeles International Film Exhibiton Certificate, March 1978 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - "Le Cinema Parallele" [Montreal], calendar, undated (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Festival Internacional de Cine Gijon [Spain], "Cuarentay Dos," lunes 29, [2004] (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - "Subway Riders," Los Angeles International Film Exposition certificate, 1982 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - 12 Internationales Forum des Jungen Films [Berlin], (32 Internationale Filmfestspiele), schedule and binder, [1982] (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - ARSENAL [Berlin], calendar, 1982 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Festival de Dequivelle du Cinema American, poster, 1971 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - New York Film Festival Program (#22), undated (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Theater Desnet Film Program "Cine D", Sept. schedule, undated (Box 43, Folder 10)
- OVERSIZE Series VI: Photography
  - Subseries A: Amos Poe Productions
    - [Amos Poe Interviews], [1979-1980] (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - "Unmade Beds," by Fernando Natalici, undated (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Subseries D: Personal Photography
    - [Alfred Hitchcock], undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - [Amos and Child], [1980] (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - [Amos Poe at Bleeker St. Cinema], undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - [Amos Poe by Peter Bellamy], [1982] (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - [Amos Poe High School Portrait], undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Charlesworth, Sarah, [1981-1982] (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - "For Gary, the Best Coffee in Town", [1978] (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - [Unidentified, B&W], undated (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - [Unidentified, color], undated (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - [Unidentified Portrait, color], undated (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - [Untitled Nature Shots, B&W], undated (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - [Unidentified Nude by Coupor], 1979 (Box 43, Folder 11)
- OVERSIZE Series VII: Visual Materials
  - Subseries B: Posters and Artwork
    - [Blond Woman with Flower], by B. Porges, [1974] (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Hans Holbein the Younger, poster, undated (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - National Peep Extra, undated (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - "The Silent Cry," poster, undated (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - [Unidentified Artwork], undated (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - Contortions, poster, undated (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - "Numero Deux," poster, undated (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - "Sauve Qui Peut (La Vie)," poster, undated (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Scala Cinema, calendar, 1979 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - "La 317 eme Section," poster, undated (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - [Woman in Red Riding Firecracker] by Willardson, poster, undated (Box 43, Folder 17)